# **Adam Hoar**

07584 573146 adam.hoar@icloud.com



## **PROFILE**

Software Engineering Bootcamp Graduate, originally coming from a background in Asset Management and Startups.

As a Full Stack Developer I get to do the things I genuinely enjoy; solving tough problems with creative solutions, being part of a team that works to build amazing things and constantly learning as I go.

Having worked on a range of projects I have experience in Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Programming, both Front and Back End, Javascript, React, Node, Express, Ruby, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Jest, Cypress and RSpec. In my own time working on some Python projects utilising Numpy, Pandas and Matplotlib.

Prior to joining Makers I was employee #4 at a <u>successful Health Care startup</u> where I gained first hand experience in Agile methodologies. Additionally, I developed as a leader over time, ultimately managing a large team of people both in the field and in person. Key to our collective success was communication, adapting quickly to new situations, learning from our mistakes and executing on our long term vision.

#### **PROJECTS**

<u>Destination Unknown</u> (Full Stack) - Javascript, React, Node, Express, HTML & CSS - TDD with Jest & Cypress

- A travel destination comparison site. Features include flight prices, budget, safety and accommodation comparison.
- A Test Driven programme developed with Aqile, daily stand-ups, retros and sprints.

Acebook (Full Stack) - MongoDB, Express, React, Node - TDD with Jest & Cypress

- A social media app that allows users to register/log in, post, edit their posts, comment on posts, like posts, delete posts and add friends.
- Built using Agile over 3 sprints covering 10 days.

Bank Tech Test (Backend) - Javascript, Node - Tested with Jest

- User can deposit, withdraw and print a statement to the terminal.
- Completed to a deadline with an emphasis on clean, readable code. 100% test coverage.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineering Student — November 2022 - March 2023

- Makers is an intensive 4 month bootcamp created and run by industry leading engineers. Producing language agnostic, self-sufficient software engineers.
- Teaching key concepts such as Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Programming and Agile. This was taught in conjunction with Full Stack Development using Javascript, React, Node, Ruby and much more.
- Working to tight time frames we completed a range of individual, paired programming and team work.
- For a full portfolio please visit my GitHub linked above.

# Operations Manager, Lifted, London — March 2020 - November 2021

- Building out new systems and process across the business and multi-disciplinary teams.
   Included projects like automating our Recruitment Funnel, building a Sales Pipeline and our own Track & Trace System.
- Helped shape the overall direction, sprint planning, bug capture/prioritisation across our apps.
- Adopted Agile methodologies for my own team such as daily stand-ups and weekly retros. The
  weekly retros allowed us to objectively look at how we worked which was crucial to being able to
  adapt and deal with the consistent fast growth of the company.

## Operations Analyst, Lifted, London — August 2019 - March 2020

- Oversaw the day-to-day management of our Carers across London. Starting with 5-10 Carers which grew to 25-30 in these early months. Building strong relationships quickly, getting buy-in to our collective mission.
- Responsible for all day-to-day finances covering invoices, expenses and company payroll.
- Created a <u>Python Programme</u> to harness the data we had to start delivering pro-active healthcare.

## Operations Associate, Parmenion Capital Partners — February 2018 - June 2018

- Part of the team responsible for processing all client asset movements accounting for millions of pounds each day.
- Stringent attention to detail with all capital allocations as all daily transactions of millions had to reconcile to the exact correct amount.

# Investment Consultant — January 2017 to February 2018

- Established and developed relationships with clients from a range of backgrounds through faceto-face meetings, phone calls and emails.
- Research and provide information on complex investment products to aid the investment decisions of our clients.
- Responsible for training new Consultants, one-to-one's and performance reviews.
- Won several competitions for new business brought onto the platform.

# Proprietary Trader G7 Currency Markets — December 2014 - November 2016

- Responsible for investing \$6 million per week in trading volume across all G7 Currency pairs.
- Rapidly process information to make balanced investment decisions with solid risk management.
- Was the first trader to test out the remote working trading platform. Executing all trades off premises, testing the platform, reporting on issues and suggesting additional features to implement.

# **EDUCATION**

**University of Plymouth** 

**MSc Finance - Merit (2:1 Equivalent)** 

**BSc Economics** 

# **HOBBIES**

Going outside my comfort zone. Going to countries where I don't speak the language, no phone data and just going for it. Recently visiting the Matterhorn and we plan on going to Everest next year. I have played golf, tennis, football, rugby, American football, squash and my knees certainly feel like it. If you hire me apologies for the sound I make as I stand up from my chair, it's involuntary.